

PROFILE

I am post doctoral researcher in Computer Engineering with FUN Team at Inria Lille Europe-Nord Research Center in France. Since July 2021, I am a Ph.D. holder in Computer Science in the Doctoral Training Unit of Mathematics, Computer Science and Applications of the University of Ngaoundéré. Apart from my technical skills, I describe myself as a cheerful person who is pleasant to work with. I have a passion for new technologies and I like the work well done.



My personal website

CONTACT

- +33 621052077
- 1 Allée des Campanules, 59000 Villeneuve d'Ascq, France.
- wsdamieno@gmail.com
- **Damien Sambo**
- R⁶ Wohwe Damien
- wsdamieno
- D 0000-0003-0599-7535
- Damien WOHWE SAMBO
- s damien.wohwe

Damien WOHWE SAMBO

Ph.D. in Computer Engineering

WORK EXPERIENCE

 The University of Lille, France | Lecturer in Computer Science

October 2022 - Today

- Wireless Sensor Networks (WSN) (M2).
- FUN Team, Inria Lille Europe-Nord, France | PostDoct researcher

June 2022 - Today

 The University Institute of Technology of Ngaoundéré | Lecturer in Computer Science

October 2020 - May 2022

- Introduction to Information Systems (BTS 1).
- Introduction to Software Engineering (BTS 1).
- Object-Oriented modelling in UML (BTS 2).
- Faculty of Science of the University of Ngaoundéré | Lecturer in Computer Science

September 2018 – May 20222022

- Introduction to Computer Science (L1MA).
- Web Application Engineering (L3IN).
- Datawarehouse (M1IN).
- Analysis and treatment of statistical data | Trainer

April 2018 - May 2022

- · Getting started with the software IBM SPSS.
- · Processing and interpretation of survey data.
- Faculty of Science of the University of Ngaoundéré | Academic assistant

November 2017 - July 2018

- Monitoring of students.
- Management of tutorials and practical works at the Department of Mathematics and Computer Science.
- Kountac inc. | Web developer & mantainer

August 2016 – Today

- Development of the web application Kountac.fr for the online sale of African products using symfony framework.
- Maintenance, adding of new functionalities and optimising.

EDUCATION

■ Ph.D. in Computer Engineering / The University of Ngaoundéré, Cameroon (Mention : Very Honourable)

April 2016 - July 2021

Doctoral Unit Training - Mathematics, Computer Science and Applications (UFD-MIAP). Thesis co-directed by the University of Bremen and the University of Ngaoundéré <u>Title</u>: "Desing of a Wireless Underground Sensor Network for Precision Agriculture"

Field of study: Internet of Underground Things (IoUT)

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

C

C++

Matlab

Python

PHP, MySQL

HTML, CSS / Bootstrap

DIGITAL SKILLS

- Windows / Ubuntu OS / Debian
- Microsoft Office, Libre Office
- Latex
- Pymakr
- Espressif ESP-IDF
- Arduino IDE
- Castalia
- Contiki / Cooja
- Symfony
- UML tools

Master of Science in Computer Engineering / The University of Ngaoundéré, Cameroon (Grade : B+ (Top 5))

October 2012 - January 2016

Systems and Software in Distributed Environments (SLED).

<u>Grade</u>: **B+** (top 5)

■ Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering / The University of Ngaoundéré, Cameroon.

October 2009 – July 2012

Computer's network and Architecture (AR).

<u>Grade</u>: **C+** (1st)

INTERNSHIP AND SCHOLARSHIP

AUF – Mathinbio Doctoral College / the National Institute for Research in Digital Science and Technology (Inria), France.

January 2022 - March 2022

ERASMUS + / The University of Bremen, Germany.

May 2021 - July 2021

Intra ACP - ERMIT Project / The University Cheikh Anta Diop of Dakar, Senegal.

December 2018 - December 2019

NETWORK AND MEMBERSHIP

Reviewer for scientific journals (see Web of science's account).

IEEE Internet of Things Journal, IEEE GLOBECOM, EURASIP (Springer), Computer Communications (Elsevier), Applied Soft Computing (Elsevier), Internation Journal of Electronics and Communications (AEÜ-Elsevier), Peerj Computer Science (PeerJ), etc.

April 2019 - Today

Responsible for monitoring training activities within the Association for the Promotion of Geomatics and Sustainable Development (AG2D), Ngaoundéré, Cameroon.

April 2018 – Today

Google Developper Group's member (GDG) of Ngaoundéré, Cameroon.

April 2016 - January 2019

SELECTED LIST OF PUBLICATIONS

Journals (4)

 A new fuzzy logic approach for reliable communications in wireless underground sensor networks

https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11276-022-03008-7

D. Wohwe Sambo, B. O. Yenke, A. Förster, J. Ndong, P. Dayang and I. Sarr *Wireless Networks (Springer Nature)*, https://doi.org/10.1007/s11276-022-03008-7, 2022.

 Combining Fuzzy Logic and K-Nearrest Neighbor Algorithm fo Recommendation Systems

http://www.mecs-press.org/ijitcs/v13n4.html

P. Dayang, C. Sepele Petsou and D. Wohwe Sambo

International Journal of Information Technology and Computer Science (IJITCS), volume 13, number 4, pp. 1 – 16, 2021.

GENERAL SKILLS

Learning capacity

Stress management

Teamwork

Supervision of students

LANGUAGES

French: Good (Fluent)

English: Fairly good (casual)

German: Very poor (beginner)

 Wireless Underground Sensor Networks Path Loss Model for Precision Agriculture (WUSN-PLM)

https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/8964471/

D. Wohwe Sambo, A. Förster, B. O. Yenke, I. Sarr, B. Gueye and P. Dayang. *IEEE Sensors Journal*, volume 20, number 10, pp. 5298 – 5313, 2020.

 Optimized Clustering Algorithms for Large Wireless Sensor Networks: A Review

https://www.mdpi.com/1424-8220/19/2/322

D. Wohwe Sambo, B. O. Yenke, A. Förster and P. Dayang. **Sensors (MDPI)**, volume 19, number 2, pp. 1–27, 2019.

International Conference (1)

 A new approach for path loss prediction in wireless underground sensor networks

https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9000669

D. Wohwe Sambo, A. Förster, B. O. Yenke, and I. Sarr

in **2019 IEEE 44th Local Computer Networks Symposium on Emerging Topics in Networking (LCN Symposium 2019),** Osnabrück,
Germany, 14 – 17th October 2019

TRAININGS AND WORKSHOPS ATTENDED

AIMS-Cameroon Mathematics and its Applications Meeting (ACMAM), Limbé, Cameroon.

12 - 14 January 2022

2nd Mathinbio doctoral college meeting (AUF), Catholic University of Central Africa (Ekounou campus), Yaoundé, Cameroon.

6 - 10 December 2021

1st International Conference Local Resource Exploiatation (LOREXP), Ngaoundéré, Cameroon.

20 - 23 April 2021

1st Mathinbio doctoral college meeting (AUF), Catholic University of Central Africa (Nkolbisson campus), Yaoundé, Cameroon.

26 - 30 October 2020

9th ConfereNce sur la Recherche en Informatique et ses Applications (CNRIA), Saint-Louis, Senegal.

25 - 28 April 2019

REFERENCES

• Anna FÖRSTER – anna.foerster@uni-bremen.de

(+49) 421 21862383

Professor, Department of Sustainable Communication Networks, the University of Bremen, Germany.

• Nathalie MITTON – nathalie.mitton@inria.fr (+33) 6 30 70 36 94

DR (Head of research group), FUN team, -, France.

• Idrissa SARR - idrissa.sarr@ucad.edu.sn

(+221) 77 626 82 31

Professor, Department of Mathematics and Computer Science, the University Cheikh Anta Diop of Dakar, Senegal.

• Blaise Omer YENKE - boyenke@univ-ndere.cm

(+237) 670 44 35 48

Associate Professor, Department of Computer Engineering, the University Institute of Technology of Ngaoundéré, Cameroon.